<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fabrício Almeida-Silva on Fabrício's personal website</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in Fabrício Almeida-Silva on Fabrício's personal website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bioinformatics in Modern Biology: computational genomics as a tool
to unravel the soybean genome and gene regulation</title><link>/talk/sbv2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talk/sbv2021/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Prioritizing soybean resistance genes against fungal diseases by integrating GWAS and gene coexpression networks</title><link>/talk/pgce2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talk/pgce2021/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Pathogenesis-related protein 1 (PR-1) genes in soybean: genome-wide identification, structural analysis and expression profiling under multiple biotic and abiotic stresses</title><link>/publications/pr1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publications/pr1/</guid><description>Abstract Plant pathogenesis-related (PR) proteins are a large group of proteins, classified in 17 families, that are induced by pathological conditions. Here, we characterized the soybean PR-1 (GmPR-1) gene repertoire at the sequence, structural and expression levels. We found 24 GmPR-1 genes, clustered in two phylogenetic groups. GmPR-1 genes are under strong purifying selection, particularly those that emerged by tandem duplications. GmPR-1 promoter regions are abundant in cis-regulatory elements associated with major stress-related transcription factor families, namely WRKY, ERF, HD-Zip, C2H2, NAC, and GATA.</description></item><item><title>Integrating omics approaches to discover and prioritize candidate genes involved in oil biosynthesis in soybean</title><link>/publications/soybeanoil/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publications/soybeanoil/</guid><description>Abstract Soybean is one of the major sources of edible protein and oil. Oil content is a quantitative trait that is significantly determined by genetic and environmental factors. Over the past 30 years, a large volume of soybean genetic, genomic, and transcriptomic data have been accumulated. Nevertheless, integrative analyses of such data remain scarce, in spite of their importance for crop improvement. We hypothesized that the co-occurrence of genomic regions for oil-related traits in different studies may reveal more stable regions encompassing important genetic determinants of oil content and quality in soybean.</description></item><item><title>Integration of genome-wide association studies and gene coexpression networks unveils promising soybean resistance genes against five common fungal pathogens</title><link>/publications/soyfungigcn/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publications/soyfungigcn/</guid><description>Abstract Soybean is one of the most important legume crops worldwide. However, soybean yield is dramatically affected by fungal diseases, leading to economic losses of billions of dollars yearly. Here, we integrated publicly available genome-wide association studies and transcriptomic data to prioritize candidate genes associated with resistance to Cadophora gregata, Fusarium graminearum, Fusarium virguliforme, Macrophomina phaseolina, and Phakopsora pachyrhizi. We identified 188, 56, 11, 8, and 3 high-confidence candidates for resistance to F.</description></item><item><title>BioNERO</title><link>/project/bionero/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/project/bionero/</guid><description>Summary BioNERO is an R/Bioconductor package that aims to facilitate network analyses by integrating all standard analysis steps, including data preprocessing, inference of gene regulatory and coexpression network from expression data, functional analyses, and network intra and interspecies network comparisons.</description></item><item><title>cageminer</title><link>/project/cageminer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/project/cageminer/</guid><description>Summary cageminer aims to integrate GWAS-derived SNPs and coexpression networks to mine candidate genes associated with a particular phenotype. For that, users must define a set of guide genes, which are known genes involved in the studied phenotype. Additionally, the mined candidates can be given a score that favor candidates that are hubs and/or transcription factors. The scores can then be used to rank and select the top n most promising genes for downstream experiments.</description></item><item><title>SoyFungiGCN</title><link>/project/soyfungigcn/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/project/soyfungigcn/</guid><description>Summary SoyFungiGCN is an R package that contains a Shiny app to let users explore a gene coexpression network inferred from RNA-seq data of soybean tissues infected with phytopathogenic fungi. The Shiny app is also available online at https://soyfungigcn.venanciogroup.uenf.br.</description></item><item><title>cageminer: an R/Bioconductor package to prioritize candidate genes by integrating GWAS and gene coexpression networks</title><link>/publications/cageminer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publications/cageminer/</guid><description>Abstract Soybean (Glycine max [L.] Merr.) is a major crop in animal feed and human nutrition, mainly for its rich protein and oil contents. The remarkable rise in soybean transcriptome studies over the past 5 years generated an enormous amount of RNA-seq data, encompassing various tissues, developmental conditions and genotypes. In this study, we have collected data from 1298 publicly available soybean transcriptome samples, processed the raw sequencing reads and mapped them to the soybean reference genome in a systematic fashion.</description></item><item><title>cageminer: mining candidate genes by integrating GWAS and gene coexpression networks</title><link>/talk/bioc2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talk/bioc2021/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Priorização de genes de resistência a fungos em soja (*Glycine max*) por meio da integração de associação genômica ampla e redes de coexpressão gênica</title><link>/talk/viconpg/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talk/viconpg/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>/contact/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/contact/</guid><description>** Contact page don&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just the front matter above. See form.html in the layouts folder **</description></item><item><title>Processing and visualizing data in the tidyverse</title><link>/teaching/tidyverse/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/teaching/tidyverse/</guid><description> Processing and visualizing data in the tidyverse</description></item><item><title>BioNERO: an all-in-one R/Bioconductor package for comprehensive and easy biological network reconstruction</title><link>/publications/bionero/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publications/bionero/</guid><description>Abstract Summary Currently, standard network analysis workflows rely on many different packages, often requiring users to have a solid statistics and programming background. Here, we present BioNERO, an R package that aims to integrate all aspects of network analysis workflows, including expression data preprocessing, gene coexpression and regulatory network inference, functional analyses, and intra and interspecies network comparisons. The state-of-the-art methods implemented in BioNERO ensure that users can perform all analyses with a single package in a simple pipeline, without needing to learn a myriad of package-specific syntaxes.</description></item><item><title>Project management in bioinformatics</title><link>/blog/2021-03-01-project-management-in-bioinformatics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021-03-01-project-management-in-bioinformatics/</guid><description>Project management in bioinformatics As we advance in bioinformatics research, we develop some practices to manage our projects and handle the deadlines and productivity goals. However, these project management skills are often not taught to new students and researchers. Thus, new researchers can have very bad habits at the beginning of their projects that can be hard to fix afterwards. Here, I highlighted my list of most important management tasks for bioinformatics projects, with examples of dos and don’ts that should be incorporated in researchers’ routines.</description></item><item><title>The state of the art in soybean transcriptomics resources and gene coexpression networks</title><link>/publications/minireview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publications/minireview/</guid><description>Abstract In the past decade, over 3000 samples of soybean transcriptomic data have accumulated in public repositories. Here, we review the state of the art in soybean transcriptomics, highlighting the major microarray and RNA-seq studies that investigated soybean transcriptional programs in different tissues and conditions. Further, we propose approaches for integrating such big data using gene coexpression network and outline important web resources that may facilitate soybean data acquisition and analysis, contributing to the acceleration of soybean breeding and functional genomics research.</description></item><item><title>Genome-Wide Analysis of the COBRA-Like Gene Family Supports Gene Expansion through Whole-Genome Duplication in Soybean (*Glycine max*)</title><link>/publications/cob/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publications/cob/</guid><description>Abstract The COBRA-like (COBL) gene family has been associated with the regulation of cell wall expansion and cellulose deposition. COBL mutants result in reduced levels and disorganized deposition of cellulose causing defects in the cell wall and inhibiting plant development. In this study, we report the identification of 24 COBL genes (GmCOBL) in the soybean genome. Phylogenetic analysis revealed that the COBL proteins are divided into two groups, which differ by about 170 amino acids in the N-terminal region.</description></item><item><title>Exploring the complexity of soybean (Glycine max) transcriptional regulation using global gene co-expression networks</title><link>/publications/globalgcn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publications/globalgcn/</guid><description>Abstract Soybean (Glycine max (L.) Merr.) is one of the most important crops worldwide, constituting a major source of protein and edible oil. Gene co-expression networks (GCN) have been extensively used to study transcriptional regulation and evolution of genes and genomes. Here, we report a soybean GCN using 1284 publicly available RNA-Seq samples from 15 distinct tissues. We found modules that are differentially regulated in specific tissues, comprising processes such as photosynthesis, gluconeogenesis, lignin metabolism, and response to biotic stress.</description></item><item><title>Systematic analysis of 1298 RNA‐Seq samples and construction of a comprehensive soybean (*Glycine max*) expression atlas</title><link>/publications/atlas/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publications/atlas/</guid><description>Abstract Soybean (Glycine max [L.] Merr.) is a major crop in animal feed and human nutrition, mainly for its rich protein and oil contents. The remarkable rise in soybean transcriptome studies over the past 5 years generated an enormous amount of RNA-seq data, encompassing various tissues, developmental conditions and genotypes. In this study, we have collected data from 1298 publicly available soybean transcriptome samples, processed the raw sequencing reads and mapped them to the soybean reference genome in a systematic fashion.</description></item><item><title>License</title><link>/license/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/license/</guid><description>My blog posts are released under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</description></item></channel></rss>