<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>WGD on Fabrício's personal website</title><link>/categories/wgd/</link><description>Recent content in WGD on Fabrício's personal website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/wgd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Genome-Wide Analysis of the COBRA-Like Gene Family Supports Gene Expansion through Whole-Genome Duplication in Soybean (*Glycine max*)</title><link>/publications/cob/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publications/cob/</guid><description>Abstract The COBRA-like (COBL) gene family has been associated with the regulation of cell wall expansion and cellulose deposition. COBL mutants result in reduced levels and disorganized deposition of cellulose causing defects in the cell wall and inhibiting plant development. In this study, we report the identification of 24 COBL genes (GmCOBL) in the soybean genome. Phylogenetic analysis revealed that the COBL proteins are divided into two groups, which differ by about 170 amino acids in the N-terminal region.</description></item><item><title>Exploring the complexity of soybean (Glycine max) transcriptional regulation using global gene co-expression networks</title><link>/publications/globalgcn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publications/globalgcn/</guid><description>Abstract Soybean (Glycine max (L.) Merr.) is one of the most important crops worldwide, constituting a major source of protein and edible oil. Gene co-expression networks (GCN) have been extensively used to study transcriptional regulation and evolution of genes and genomes. Here, we report a soybean GCN using 1284 publicly available RNA-Seq samples from 15 distinct tissues. We found modules that are differentially regulated in specific tissues, comprising processes such as photosynthesis, gluconeogenesis, lignin metabolism, and response to biotic stress.</description></item></channel></rss>