<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>coexpression network on Fabrício&#39;s personal website</title>
    <link>/categories/coexpression-network/</link>
    <description>Recent content in coexpression network on Fabrício&#39;s personal website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/coexpression-network/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>BioNERO: an all-in-one R/Bioconductor package for comprehensive and easy biological network reconstruction</title>
      <link>/publications/bionero/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/bionero/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   Summary Currently, standard network analysis workflows rely on many different packages, often requiring users to have a solid statistics and programming background. Here, we present BioNERO, an R package that aims to integrate all aspects of network analysis workflows, including expression data preprocessing, gene coexpression and regulatory network inference, functional analyses, and intra and interspecies network comparisons. The state-of-the-art methods implemented in BioNERO ensure that users can perform all analyses with a single package in a simple pipeline, without needing to learn a myriad of package-specific syntaxes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The state of the art in soybean transcriptomics resources and gene coexpression networks</title>
      <link>/publications/minireview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/minireview/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   In the past decade, over 3000 samples of soybean transcriptomic data have accumulated in public repositories. Here, we review the state of the art in soybean transcriptomics, highlighting the major microarray and RNA-seq studies that investigated soybean transcriptional programs in different tissues and conditions. Further, we propose approaches for integrating such big data using gene coexpression network and outline important web resources that may facilitate soybean data acquisition and analysis, contributing to the acceleration of soybean breeding and functional genomics research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the complexity of soybean (Glycine max) transcriptional regulation using global gene co-expression networks</title>
      <link>/publications/globalgcn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/globalgcn/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   Soybean (Glycine max (L.) Merr.) is one of the most important crops worldwide, constituting a major source of protein and edible oil. Gene co-expression networks (GCN) have been extensively used to study transcriptional regulation and evolution of genes and genomes. Here, we report a soybean GCN using 1284 publicly available RNA-Seq samples from 15 distinct tissues. We found modules that are differentially regulated in specific tissues, comprising processes such as photosynthesis, gluconeogenesis, lignin metabolism, and response to biotic stress.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
