<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>bioinformatics on Fabrício's personal website</title><link>/categories/bioinformatics/</link><description>Recent content in bioinformatics on Fabrício's personal website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/bioinformatics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Project management in bioinformatics</title><link>/blog/2021-03-01-project-management-in-bioinformatics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021-03-01-project-management-in-bioinformatics/</guid><description>Project management in bioinformatics As we advance in bioinformatics research, we develop some practices to manage our projects and handle the deadlines and productivity goals. However, these project management skills are often not taught to new students and researchers. Thus, new researchers can have very bad habits at the beginning of their projects that can be hard to fix afterwards. Here, I highlighted my list of most important management tasks for bioinformatics projects, with examples of dos and don’ts that should be incorporated in researchers’ routines.</description></item><item><title>Pushing Docker images to Docker Hub</title><link>/blog/2021-12-01-push_image_dockerhub/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021-12-01-push_image_dockerhub/</guid><description>Pushing Docker images to Docker Hub This post assumes you already have an account on Docker Hub. If you don&amp;rsquo;t, sign up for free before going any further.
Once you have a Docker Hub account, log in and create the repository where you want to store the image. You can do that by clicking the Create Repository button.
Building the image To push an image to Docker Hub, you will need to have it on your machine.</description></item></channel></rss>