<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>software on Fabrício's personal website</title><link>/categories/software/</link><description>Recent content in software on Fabrício's personal website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Integrating omics approaches to discover and prioritize candidate genes involved in oil biosynthesis in soybean</title><link>/publications/soybeanoil/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publications/soybeanoil/</guid><description>Abstract Soybean is one of the major sources of edible protein and oil. Oil content is a quantitative trait that is significantly determined by genetic and environmental factors. Over the past 30 years, a large volume of soybean genetic, genomic, and transcriptomic data have been accumulated. Nevertheless, integrative analyses of such data remain scarce, in spite of their importance for crop improvement. We hypothesized that the co-occurrence of genomic regions for oil-related traits in different studies may reveal more stable regions encompassing important genetic determinants of oil content and quality in soybean.</description></item><item><title>BioNERO: an all-in-one R/Bioconductor package for comprehensive and easy biological network reconstruction</title><link>/publications/bionero/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publications/bionero/</guid><description>Abstract Summary Currently, standard network analysis workflows rely on many different packages, often requiring users to have a solid statistics and programming background. Here, we present BioNERO, an R package that aims to integrate all aspects of network analysis workflows, including expression data preprocessing, gene coexpression and regulatory network inference, functional analyses, and intra and interspecies network comparisons. The state-of-the-art methods implemented in BioNERO ensure that users can perform all analyses with a single package in a simple pipeline, without needing to learn a myriad of package-specific syntaxes.</description></item></channel></rss>